Guide to the Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie Papers,
1896-1904
Hobbes, John Oliver, 1867-1906.
0.5 linear ft (24 items in 1 box).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078661
History
Anglo-American novelist and dramatist. Pearl Craigie wrote under the pseudonym John Oliver Hobbes.
Scope and Content
Correspondence of Craigie; and the holograph manuscript for her novel, The Serious Wooing.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 2 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Works
Subjects
American literature--20th century.; Manuscripts.; Women authors, American.; Women dramatists, American.; British Americans.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
M-59 Purchase
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence, 1885-1916
  The series contains incoming and outgoing correspondence of Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie. It is arranged chronologically, with undated material at the end of the series.
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Theresa To: Annie [Richards], London, 28 June 1885, (31p. a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To: Nell [Ellen Ternan], n.p., November 1896, (1p. a.n.s.) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To: Dorothy Richards, December 1896, ( 3 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl May Teresa To: Miss Curtis, 20 March 1897, (2 p. a.l.s. (in the hand of Zoe proctor, her secretary)) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl mary Teresa To: Miss Curtis, 25 February 1898, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To: "Dear Madam", 17 March 1898, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To: Mrs. Halsey, 26 November 1898, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To: Miss Curtis, 3 March 1899, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To: Miss Curtis, 10 April 1899, (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie, Stocks Tring England, 10 March 1902, (4 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To Arthur Christopher Benson, 26 March 1904, (3p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - [Richards, Dorothy] To: John Morgan Richards, London, 30 November 1916, (2p. a.l. (by a Lady in Waiting for the Queen of England)) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To Miss Curtis, 7 March [n.y.], (1 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa To: Miss Curtis, London, n.d., (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie, n.d., (5 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie a.l.s., 2 p., The Priory [Reigate, Yorkshire], [n.d.], (2 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie, [n.d.], ( 3 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie, Carlton Gardens, 18 March, [n.y.], (3 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie, 18 May, n.y., (3 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie, The Priory, Reigate [Yorkshire], 3 June [n.y.], (4 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie, 4 September [n.y.], (4 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta Arnold (Mrs. Humphrey) To: Pearl Mary Teresa Craigie, 18 September [n.y.], (4 p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
- Series II: Works
  The series consists of the annotated manuscript of Craigie's book The Serious Wooing, written under the pen name of John Oliver Hobbes, and a bookplate autographed by Craigie.
  - Bookplate (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Serious Wooing, n.d. (Published by Methuen in 1901)., (97 p. a.ms. novel ) (Box 1)